## **Eduard Bartosh**

# Software Engineer

Areas of expertise: Python development, Linux build systems, software integration, strong general IT and Unix expertise. Work well independently and within a team. Self-starter with minimal amount of instructions and supervision required.

Address: Meri-Rastilan tie 17G 62 00980 Helsinki, Finland

**Phone:** +358 50 4868859 **Email:** bartosh@gmail.com

**Date of Birth:** July 2, 1965 **Marital Status:** married

## **Professional Experience**

### 2011-now

**Intel Corporation** 

Senior Linux Software Engineer

- Developed tools for package building in Python
- Maintained Jenkins and OBS build systems
- Implemented support for patch series for Patchwork
- · Configured and administrated build farm

#### 2004-2011

**Nokia Corporation** 

Senior Design Engineer

- Designed, developed and maintained build&intergation system for Nokia linux-based mobile devices
- Designed and developed repository management software
- Designed and developed Continuous Integration system
- Maintained kernel and core userspace packages
- Maintained Maemo SDK packages
- Designed and developed localisation infrastructure for Maemo software

Maemo Community

Developer, Packager, root@maemo

- Ported and maintained several projects for Maemo: OpenSSH, Evince, TuxType
- Packaged Enlightenment Foundation Libraries for Maemo
- Packaged IPython and helped with developing building infrastructure for Python for Maemo
- Designed, developed and mantained Maemo autobuilder
- Ported Mnemosyne learning tool for Maemo
- Taking part in GSoC 2009 as a mentor
- Built base system for Emdebian project using Maemo packages and modified tools from Debian

#### 2003-2004

#### Alt Linux team

Package maintainer, member of Alt Linux kernel committee

- Adopted Linux kernel 2.6 and kernel modules packages for ALT Linux distribution
- Packaged isakmpd (IPSEC daemon) for ALT Linux
- Maintained server-oriented kernel package (kernel-image-aw) and other packages for Alt Linux
- Took part in the development of the debian-like built scheme for ALT Linux kernel-related packages

#### 2001-2004

Software development company "SaM Solutions"

Software developer

- Developed hotswap subsysystem (userspace and kernel space parts)
- SCSI,Im\_sensors and NICs boot detection and configuration (shell scripting)
- Linux kernel: dm (device mapper) fix for GETSIZE64 (allows to create XFS volumes >1Tb on the EVMS devices)
- Linux kernel: fixes for net\_mod package and Alacritech TOE NIC driver
- Linux kernel: developed I18N functionality to NFSD
- Linux kernel: developed uid/gid mapping to NFSD
- Linux kernel: adopted pdcraid module for FastTrack software RAID controller
- ApplianceWare: developed and maintained Network Attached Storage server-side software
- ApplianceWare: implemented POSIX ACL(Access Control Lists) functionality
- ApplianceWare: integrated ADS(Advanced Directory Services)
- ApplianceWare: packaged and maintained Linux kernel

## Education

**1982-1988:** Master's Degree in Electrical Engineering in Saint Petersburg State University of Aerospace Instrumentation, Russia

## Technical skills

Operation Unix/Linux

Systems:

Programming strong knowledge of Python, moderate: C, Shell, some: C++, Ruby, Erlang

languages:

VCS tools: git, svn, cvs, mercurial, bazaarDatabases: MySQL, PostgreSQL, DB2

Internet: TCP/IP, HTML, XML

# Languages

Russian: Native English: Good Finnish: Basic

Last updated: March 29, 2012

Original http://www.bartosh.org/cv.html

document:

**Pdf version:** http://www.bartosh.org/cv.pdf